A Guide to the William M. Connor Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
William M. Connor Papers 1907-1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3287
This collection consists of ca. 6500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The William Mellard Connor Papers were a gift from Colonel William M. Connor, Jr., USA on 26 August 1949.
Biographical/Historical Information
William Mellard Connor was born on 31 August 1878, the son of William M. Connor (1847-1922) and Theresa Olivia Moores Connor (1847-1932). He married Artemisia Katharine Peyton on 26 October 1911. They had one son, William M. Connor, Jr., born on 27 October 1912.
Connor received his B.A. from Wofford College, South Carolina, in 1897, and from January 1899 through June 1900, was enrolled as a special student at the University of Virginia Law School. He received an LL.B. from the University of Virginia in 1923, and from 1928 to 1929 did graduate work in law at Harvard University. The Pennsylvania Military College presented Connor with an honorary Doctor of Military Law in 1943.
Connor's legal career was extensive and varied. From 1902 to 1920, he served in the Philippines, entering the Philippine civil service from South Carolina in 1902. In 1903, he was appointed Assisant Attorney for the Moro Province, and served successively as attorney for the Moro Province, 1908 to 1914; City Attorney of Manila, 1914; and as Judge, Court of First Instance, Eighteenth Judicial District, 1914 to 1918.
In December 1917, he was appointed Major, Judge Advocate of the Reserve Corps. From 1918 to 1920, he was a member of the Department of the Judge Advocate and served on the General Board of Review, the Special Clemency Board, and the Military Justice Board of Review, J. A. G. O.
Connor served under General Enoch H. Crowder in Cuba from January through March 1921, and later joined the War Department General Staff in Washington, D. C. He served two tours of duty as a professor of law at West Point, and upon his retirement as a Colonel in 1944, he did research in military law at the University of Virginia.
His scholarly writings were mainly in the areas of military law and the administration of military justice. He was a member of the South Carolina, Philippine Islands, and United States Supreme Court Bars.
Scope and Content Information
The William M. Connor Papers, 1907-1949 include correspondence, speeches, drafts of articles, legal research notes, a military justice legal file, and a number of miscellaneous items which document Connor's career as a Judge Advocate in the United States Army.
Correspondence of particular interest include papers concerning the court martial controversy of 1918-1919; correspondence with Roscoe Pound concerning study at Harvard Law School during the academic year 1927- 1928; papers containing a Latin-American legal delegation visit to the University of Virginia Law School in 1945; miscellaneous correspondence concerning the Moro Province, Philippines, 1907-1913; and correspondence concerning Connor's appointment to a judgeship in 1914.
Correspondents of interest include Walter P. Armstrong, former President of the American Bar Association; Lt. Col. A. B. Butts; James F. Byrnes; General Enoch H. Crowder; Roscoe Pound; J. S. Powell; and Daniel R. Williams.
The military justice legal file, 1940-1943, consists of memoranda and reports together with a small amount of correspondence which pertains to the various topics covered in the file.
Arrangement
Colonel Connor had a general correspondence file, 1907-1949, arranged alphabetically by topic or individual. This arrangement has been preserved and is located in boxes 1 through 4. Boxes 4 through 6 contain his files of military justice legal papers, Second Army and West Point, 1940-1943.
Boxes 7 through 8 contain Connor's talks, 1915-1945, and articles, 1925-1944, respectively. Boxes 8 through 10 contain legal research notes, 1914-1947, arranged chronologically by topical folder. Box 10 also contains his Military Regulations Legal Source Folder of index cards, ca. 1946-ca. 1947, arranged alphabetically.
The miscellaneous items, 1912-1947, are arranged chronologically in boxes 11 through 13, and are followed by the printed material, 1910-1949, in boxes 13 and 14.
Contents List
- The Academy of Political Science to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1945, 1948 (Box 1)
  4 items
- Correspondence with the Adjutant General's Office, War Department, Washington, D. C. 1944-1948 (Box 1)
  ca. 8 items
- Wm. M. Connor to Dr. Edwin A. Alderman 1929 Jan 20, AL (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Alderman Library re: books borrowed, gifts, study 1945-1949 (Box 1)
  ca. 80 items
- Correspondence with the American Military Institute 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  5 items
- Correspondence with the American Unitarian Association 1928, TNS (Box 1)
- Correspondence and papers re: Ancestry 1932-1939 (Box 1)
  ca. 36 items
- Correspondence with Kenneth Anderson, Clerk, House of Representatives, Committee on Military Affairs 1939 (Box 1)
  7 items
- Correspondence and papers re: various applications 1919-1920 (Box 1)
  ca. 20 items
- Correspondence with Walter Armstrong, attorney and former president of the American Bar Association 1942-1946 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and paper re: the Army as an aid of the civil power 1922 Oct. (Box 1)
  2 items
- Correspondence and papers re: The Army and Navy Club 1944-1946 (Box 1)
  3 items
- S. Arundale to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1945 Jan 9, TLS (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Anne Betts 1942 May (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Lt. Col. A. B. Butts 1943 (Box 1)
  8 items
- Correspondence with James F. Byrnes 1945 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and papers re: Cadet Entrance Requirements proposal of military personality, leadership qualifications 1943 (Box 1)
  ca. 6 items
- Correspondence with Charles R. Cameron 1945, 1946 (Box 1)
- Robert E. Chandler to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1946 Mar 19, TLS (Box 1)
- Correspondence and papers re: Change of Station, from J. A. Second Army to Professor of Law U. S. M. A. 1941-1943 (Box 1)
  ca. 25 items
- Correspondence with Alfonso M. Cinco 1917-1924 (Box 1)
  17 items
- Correspondence with the Committee for Constitutional Government 1944 Apr (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Mr. and Mrs. Connor, parents of Col. Wm. M. Connor 1919-1929 (Box 1)
- Col Wm. M. Connor to Wm. M. Connor, Jr. 1943 Feb 2 (Box 1)
- Correspondence and papers re: Court-Martial controversy 1918-1919 (Box 1)
  ca. 30 items
- Correspondence and papers re: Court-Martial System Revision 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  ca. 28 items
- Correspondence with General Enoch H. Crowder 1921-1926 (Box 2)
  16 items
- E. A. Gilmore to Major Wm. M. Connor 1929 Jan 23, TLS (Box 2)
- Fyke Farmer to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1948 Aug 9, TLS (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Hamilton Fish 1943 (Box 2)
- Edward W. Fox to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1939 Nov 28, TLS (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Garrard Glenn, Professor of Law, University of Virginia Law School 1945 (Box 2)
  ca. 9 items
- Correspondence with Garner W. Green, attorney 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  6 items
- Correspondence with Brig. Gen. Thomas H. Green 1941-1948 (Box 2)
  ca. 10 items
- Wesley W. K. Hamlton to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1928 Jan 27, AN (Box 2)
- Correspondence and papers re: study at Harvard Law School, includes correspondence with Roscoe Pound re: course of study 1927-1929 (Box 2)
  ca. 40 items
- Correspondence: Miscellaneous Harvard Law School, Harvard University 1942-1948 (Box 1)
- Lt. Col. H. H. Hasting to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1945 May 1, TLS (Box 2)
- Miss Mary Oakley Hay to Col. Wm. M. Connor n.d., AN (Box 2)
- Correspondence, legal papers re: "Hearsay in Military Law" 1931-1945 (Box 2)
- International Bar Association to Wm. M. Connor 1949 May 18, TL (Box 2)
- Correspondence re: Judge Advocate Association 1945-1946 (Box 2)
  ca. 13 items
- Correspondence and papers: miscellaneous re: Connor as Corps Area Judge Advocate, Chicago, Illinois 1922-1938 (Box 2)
- Correspondence with the Judge Advocate General Office, mainly re: materials for Connor's legal research 1943-1949 (Box 2)
  ca. 86 items
- Correspondence, memoranda, and papers: Miscellaneous J. A. G. ca. 1918-1923 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, memoranda, and papers re: J. A. Second Army (special file), mainly Documentary Data pertaining to Office memorandum 1941 (Box 2)
  ca. 27 items
- Correspondence, research notes, and papers re: an article, "The Judgemental Review in General Court-Martial Proceedings" ca. 1941-1945 (Box 3)
  ca. 78 items
- "Billy" [Connor] to Dear "K" n.d., ALS (Box 3)
- Col. Archibald King to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1945 Jan 20, TLS (Box 3)
- Correspondence, notes, papers re: Latin American Group visit including notes for a talk, "[Conceptos Constituteros de Nuestro Sistema de Cousejos de Guerra]" 1945 (Box 2)
  ca. 52 items
- Correspondence and papers re: Law Course, Materials for use of Instructors in Law Dept. Classroom work 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  ca. 35 items
- Correspondence and papers re: Spanish and American Law Library gift to the University Law Library 1946-1949 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and law notes 1925-1926 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and law notes, provisional file 1924-1925 (Box 3)
- Brig. Gen. E. R. W. McCabe to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1945 Feb 8, ALS (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Brig. Gen. E. C. McNeil 1946 (Box 3)
- W. W. Marquardt to Major Wm. M. Connor 1918 Apr 30, TLS (Box 3)
- Correspondence and papers re: Moro Province, Philippines (miscellaneous) 1907-1913 (Box 3)
  ca. 14 items
- Correspondence: North American Accident Insurance Co. 1928, TLS (Box 3)
- Correspondence and papers re: various periodical subscriptions 1945-1949 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and papers re: various Philippine Anecdotes 1908-1918 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and papers re: Philippine Government Claims of Wm. M. Connor 1917-1920 (Box 3)
- Correspondence re: Philippine Judgeship Appointment 1914 (Box 11 items)
- Roscoe Pound to Maj. Wm. M. Connor 1928 Dec 22, ANS (Box 3)
- Correspondence with J. S. Powell 1914 (Box 3)
- Arthur C. Purvis to Mr. Frank Degnan n.d., TL (Box 3)
- Correspondence re: Request for a leave of absence of Wm. M. Connor, Jr. as Judge, Nineteenth Judicial District, Philippines 1919-1920 (Box 3)
  ca. 24 items
- Retired Officers Association to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1948 Jul 1, TL (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Sam Houston State Bank and Trust Co. 1929 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and papers: Miscellaneous Second Division material 1925-1928 (Box 3)
  ca. 15 items
- Marion H. Smoak to Col. Charles W. West and Col. Wm. M. Connor 1947 Nov 13, TL (Box 3)
- Henry Nelson Snyder to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1946 Feb 5, ALS (Box 3)
- Ildefnozo T. Yu Biao Sontua to Wm. M. Connor n.d., TN (Box 3)
- Correspondence with the South Carolina Bar Association 1939-1948 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and notes re: Surrender of Military persons to Civil Authorities 1928, 1946 (Box 3)
- Correspondence with the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Unitarian Church 1949 (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Benjamin R. Tillman, Chairman of Senate Committee on Naval Affairs 1917 (Box 4)
- Correspondence and papers re: the Twentieth Century Fund 1945-1946 (Box 4)
  12 items
- Correspondence with Col. Lewis K. Underhill 1945-1946 (Box 4)
- Correspondence and papers re: United Services Automobile Association 1935-1936 (Box 4)
- Correspondence and papers re: Graduation Exercises at the U. S. Military Academy 1942-1943 (Box 4)
- Correspondence and papers re: University of Virginia 1912-1947 (Box 4)
  ca. 55 items
- Correspondence with the University of Virginia Law School Association 1945 (Box 4)
- Correspondence with the Virginia Law Review 1923-1925 (Box 4)
- Correspondence and papers re: War Department Publications 1946-1949 (Box 4)
  20 items
- Correspondence and papers re: Washington Loan and Trust Co. 1942 (Box 4)
  ca. 23 items
- Correspondence and papers re: West Coast Life Insurance Co. 1931-1935 (Box 4)
  ca. 12 items
- H. A. White to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1943 Nov 8, TLS (Box 4)
- Daniel R. Williams to Major Wm. M. Connor 1928 Jul 26, TL (Box 4)
- Correspondence with Major Clarence L. Yancey 1945 (Box 4)
- Col. Edward H. Young to Col. Wm. M. Connor 1942 Oct 27, TLS (Box 4)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - A 1940-1943 (Box 4)
  38 items (4 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - B 1941-1943 (Box 4)
  12 items (3 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - C 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  ca. 58 items (2 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - C 1943 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - D 1940-1943 (Box 5)
  ca. 55 items (4 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - E 1941-1943 (Box 5)
  ca. 21 items (3 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - F & G 1941-1943 (Box 5)
  39 items (6 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - H 1940-1943 (Box 5)
  16 items (4 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - I 1941 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - J 1940-1943 (Box 5)
  27 items (4 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - L 1940-1943 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - M 1941 (Box 5)
  ca. 17 items
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - M 1942-1943 (Box 6)
  ca. 7 items (2 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - N 1941 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - O 1940-1943 (Box 6)
  ca. 19 items (4 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - P 1941-1943 (Box 6)
  ca. 15 items (Box 6)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - R, S and T 1941-1943 (Box 6)
  ca. 77 items (9 folders)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - V 1941 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, memoranda and reports - W 1940, 1942 (Box 6)
- Notes and papers for a talk re: Federal Martial Law 1818-1947 (Box 7)
- Talk re: The Declaration of Independence ca. 1915, TMs (Box 7)
- Lecture, "Command Power of the President," delivered to the First Class on Dec. 19 and 20, 1935 and in Dec, 1936 1935-1936, TMs (Box 7)
- Farewell Address, West Point 1936-1943 (Box 7)
- Lecture, "Judicial Outline of Federal Martial Law within the United States as a Constitutional Exertion of Command Power" [ca. 1936], TMs (Box 7)
- Lecture, "Federal Military Aid to the Civil Power," includes research notes and a list of occasions when federal aid was used [ca. 1936-1937] (Box 7)
  ca. 19 items
- Notes for a lecture re: the Nature of Law, U. S. M. A. 1937-1943 (Box 7)
- Notes for a lecture re: When and How to Prosecute in Military Justice Administration 1942-1943 (Box 7)
  ca. 11 items
- Lecture re: larceny and embezzlement by Col. Connor 1943 Apr 15 (Box TMs)
- Notes for a lecture re: Law of Domestic Disturbances 1943 (Box 7)
- Address and notes re: Post-trial process of Adjudication 1945 (Box 7)
- Address re: WWII and the U. S. Army, the "law extending" organization n.d., AMs (Box 7)
- Talk, "The National Significance of the Day" n.d., 2 TMs (Box 7)
- Notes for an Address: "American in the Philippines" n.d. (Box 7)
- Article, "Reviewing authority in Court-Martial Proceedings," includes manuscript and typescript 1925 (Box 7)
- Thesis, "The Government of the Moro Province: A Legal Experiment in the Delegation of General Leglislative power to a Local Legislative Body" 1928-1929, AMs (Box 7)
- Thesis, "The Government of the Moro Province: A Legal Experiment in the Delegation of General Legislative power to a Local Legislative Body," by Wm. Connor 1928-1929, 2 TMs (Box 8)
- Research materials re: the article, "Legal aspects of the determinative review of general Court-Martial Cases under Article of War 50 1/2" 1929-ca. 1944 (Box 8)
- Report, "Federal Martial Law within the United States as a Constitutional Exertion of Command Power," includes research notes; given at S. C. Bar Assoc. on 150th anniversary of the Constitution 1938 (Box 8)
- Article, "Legal aspects of the determinative review of general Court-Martial Cases under Article of War 50 1/2," includes manuscript, typescript, and notes 1944 (Box 8)
- Paper, "Basic legal factors in Court-Martial Prosecution of Army Personnel" n.d., AMs (Box 8)
- Paper, "Philippine Public Law and its relation to the United States: Philippine Criminal Procedure" n.d., TMs (Box 8)
- Paper, "Pride and Progress" n.d., AMs (Box 8)
- Notes re: Perjury 1914 (Box 8)
- Papers and memoranda re: Military Prisioners and Military Court-Martial Procedures 1917-1944 (Box 8)
  ca. 21 items
- Notes and legal papers re: Applicability of Judicial safeguards of the Constitution to Trials by Court-Martial ca. 1917 (Box 9)
  ca. 4 items
- Legal Papers: Miscellaneous Memoranda of Wm. M. Connor as Judge Advocate 1918-1930 (Box 9)
- Notes and papers re: Homicide under Spanish Law 1922, n.d. (Box 9)
- Papers re: Efficiency Report Data 1924-1928 (Box 9)
- Legal papers: Records of trial by general Court-Martial 1924-ca. 1929 (Box 9)
  ca. 27 items (carbons)
- Notes and legal papers re: evidence 1925 (Box 9)
- Notes and papers re: Rule-making Exercise of Military Command Power over Military Establishment under the Constitution ca. 1925- ca. 1944 (Box 9)
  ca. 32 items
- Notes and legal papers re: Insanity as a Defense in Military Law ca. 1926-1944 (Box 9)
  ca. 16 items
- Memorandum re: Criticism of Civilians or Civic organizations by officers of the Army 1927 Mar 7 (Box 9)
  1 item
- Notes: Miscellaneous 1928-1947, n.d. (Box 9)
- Notes and papers re: Considerations of Law, Court-Martial Prosecution, when to prosecute ca. 1928 - ca. 1941 (Box 9)
- Thesis notes re: Congressional authority in the territories ca. 1928 - ca. 1929, n.d. (Box 9)
  ca. 7 items
- Legal papers re: Government use of Unlawfully (and lawfully) Seized Evidence in Court-Martial Proceedings against the party adversely affected by such seizure 1929, 1932 (Box 9)
- Notes re: Studies in articles of war crimes and court-martial prosecution under military law ca. 1931 - ca. 1945 (Box 9)
  ca. 18 items
- Notes and legal papers re: the U.S. vs. Hall and McPaddin 1932 (Box 9)
- Papers re: J. A. G. O. Set-up; Judge Avocate Activities therein and in field 1935-1943 (Box 9)
- Notes from Smith's Elementary Law re: property ca. 1937 (Box 9)
  ca. 5 items
- Notes and legal papers re: Procedure in cases of Cadet misconduct evincing character failure 1937-1945 (Box 9)
- Notes re: Evidence 1940 (Box 9)
- Papers and Memoranda re: Visit of Board of Consultants to West Point 1942 (Box 9)
- Court Case, The United States vs. H. R. Matthews, Sheriff of Russell Co., Alabama 1943 (Box 9)
- Notes re: Military Districts 1944 (Box 9)
- Papers and notes re: Unique Technique of Military Law [ca. 1944] (Box 9)
- Papers re: Military Occupation Courts and the case of U. S. vs. Kei Yuri, Yokohama, Japan 1945 (Box 10)
- Notes re: Technique of the Law (general) 1945 (Box 10)
- Notes and legal papers re: Supervision by Habeas Corpus of Court-Martial Proceedings ca. 1946 (Box 10)
- Notes re: Locutions - legal and other [ca. 1946] (Box 10)
- Notes re: Philippine Republic Affairs ca. 1947 (Box 10)
- Notes and papers re: Court-Martial Prosecution of Military Persons for non-military crimes 1947 (Box 10)
- Notes re: the Articles of War of 1920 n.d. (Box 10)
- Military Legal Source File, inlcudes bibliography cards, A-W [ca. 1946 - ca. 1947] (Box 10)
  ca. 500 items
- Report, "Economic conditions of Samar," by Division Superintendent of Schools 1912, TMs (Box 11)
- Looseleaf from a binder labeled, "General Instructions/Philippine Department/Maj. Wm. Connor, Jr." ca. 1913 - ca. 1918 (Box 11)
- "Views on Philippine Question, expressed in letter to D. D. Wallace of August 24, 1915" 1915, TMs (Box 11)
- Map of the World, Map of Charlottesville 1922, n.d. (Box 11)
- Notebook of lectures re: Evidence 1923 (Box 11)
- Lecture Notes re: History of English Law 1928-1929 (Box 11)
- Roman Law Readings, of Wm. M. Connor, Maj. G. A. G. D., at Harvard Law School ca. 1928-1929 (Box 11)
- Lecture Notes re: Roman Law 1928 Sep - 1929 May (Box 12)
  2 items (2 folders)
- Lecture Notes re: Jurisprudence 1928 Sep - 1929 May (Box 12)
- Papers re: Physical Examinations 1929 (Box 12)
- Papers re: Military Justice Administration - Questions and solutions - JAG - Res. Army Correspondence Course 1930-1932 (Box 12)
- Calendar, Corps of Cadets 1934 (Box 12)
- "A Testing Schedule for Combat Officers in the Army" [ca. 1941] (Box 12)
- Date Book of Col. and Mrs. Wm. M. Connor 1941 (Box 12)
- Notes and research papers: U. S. Military Government 1941-1947 (Box 12)
- Papers re: Vaccination, Tetanus Immunization, Blood Typing, etc. of Col. Wm. M. Connor 1942 (Box 12)
- Papers re: Increase of Corps of Cadets 1942 (Box 12)
- Introductory Remarks of Charles Cheever, Asst. Professor of Law for a course in Evidence at West Point 1942 (Box 12)
- "Report of Investigation re: 304th Aviation Squadron," by C. B. Finnegan, Jr., Maj. AUS 1943 Feb 24, TMs (carbon) (Box 13)
- Papers re: First Class (West Point) Comittee Affairs 1943 (Box 13)
- Empty Envelopes 1944-1946 (Box 13)
- Miscellaneous desk items [ca. 1944] (Box 13)
  22 items
- Address list for distribution of Reprints of Articles [ca. 1945-1946] (Box 13)
- Miscellaneous address and advertisement ca. 1945 (Box 13)
- Appointment Book of Col. Wm. M. Connor 1947 (Box 13)
- Red Leather Book Cover n.d. (Box 13)
- Programs for the entertainment of the Honorable Jacob M. Dickinson, Sec. of War 1910 Aug 23 (Box 13)
- Printed material: Copy of a Law enacted by the Philippine Comission on 29 Dec 1910 1910, 1911 (Box 13)
- Printed material: "Report of the Committee on Military Law," written with comments inserted by Connor 1919 (Box 13)
- Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, "Military Penal Law: A Brief Survey" 1921 May (Box 13)
  1 item (photocopy)
- Printed material: Harvard "President's Report" 1931-1933 (Box 13)
- Program, "Sixteenth Annual National Reunion of the 80th Division" 1935 Aug, 1 item (Box 13)
- Newsclippings re: Criminal Procedure Data ca. 1936 (Box 13)
- Printed Material: Miscellaneous ca. 1936 - ca. 1946 (Box 13)
- Papers and newsclippings re: Powers of the U. S. Government in War-time 1941-1945 (Box 13)
  ca. 38 items
- Newsclippings re: Saboteur Case Trial by Military Comission 1942 (Box 13)
- Printed Material: Report of the U. S. Delegation, United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization 1943 (Box 13)
- Newsclippings: Miscellaneous 1943 (Box 13)
- Printed Material: Unitarian Sermons and Pamphlets 1944-1945 (Box 13)
- Newsclippings: Miscellaneous re: WWII 1944-1945 (Box 13)
- Newspaper Clippings, mainly re: the Army, WWII, politics, and miscellaneous topics 1946-1947 (Box 13)
  ca. 75 items
- Biographical papers re: Col. Wm. M. Connor ca. 1946 (Box 14)
- Clippings re: Labor problems 1946, n.d. (Box 14)
- Newspaper Clippings re: War Crimes Trials 1947 (Box 14)
- Printed Material: Book Advertisements [ca. 1947] (Box 14)
- Printed Material: Interstate Quarantine Regulations 1948 (Box 14)
- Printed Material: Army Regulations 1948-1949 (Box 14)
  ca. 85 items
- Harvard Law Review, vol. 62, no. 1 1948 (Box 14)
- Printed Material: Communism in the U.S.A. 1948 (Box 14)
- Printed Material: Military Justice Publications under Articles of War Revision of June 25, 1948 1949 (Box 14)
- Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Vol. XXIII, no. 2 1949 (Box 14)
- Printed Materials: Arabic, probably the Koran n.d. (Box 14)
- Articles of War, Comparative Print, showing changes proposed by Judge Advocate General as compared with the changes proposed by the Kernan - O'Ryan Odgen Board and with the Existing Law n.d.